World War II had its heroes and its miracles.
Miracle at St. Anna is a drama, war film directed by Spike Lee.
Miracle at St.
Anna chronicles the story of four American soldiers who are members of the all-black 92nd
"Buffalo Soldier" Division stationed in Tuscany, Italy during World War II.
2nd Staff Sergeant Aubrey Stamps, played by Derek Luke.
Sergeant Bishop Cummings, played by Michael Ealy.
Corporal Hector Negron, played by Laz Alonso.
Private First Class Sam Train, played by Omar Benson Miller.
Peppi 'The Great Butterfly' Grotta, played by Pierfrancesco Favino.
Renata, played by Valentina Cervi.
Miracle at St.
Anna is a 2008 epic war film directed by Spike Lee and written
by James McBride, based on McBride's 2003 novel.
The film stars Derek Luke, Michael Ealy, Laz Alonso, Omar Benson Miller, Pierfrancesco Favino and
Valentina Cervi, with John Turturro, Joseph Gordon Levitt, John Leguizamo, D.B.
Sweeney and Kerry Washington in supporting roles.
Set primarily in Italy during the Italian campaign of World War II, the film tells the story of four Buffalo Soldiers of the
92nd Infantry Division who seek refuge in a small Tuscan village, where they form a bond with the residents.
The story is presented as a flashback, as one survivor, Hector Negron (Alonso),
reflects upon his experiences in a frame story set in 1980s New York.
Several real-life events that occurred during the war, such as the Sant'Anna
di Stazzema massacre, are re-enacted, placing Miracle at St.
Anna within the genre of historical fiction.
The film is a co-production of the United States and Italy.
Lee first learned of the novel in 2004 and approached
McBride with the idea of a film adaptation.
In Europe, the film's development attracted the attention of Italian film producers Roberto
Cicutto and Luigi Musini, who helped finance the $45 million production.
A majority of the film was shot in Italy, on several
locations affected by World War II.
Other filming locations included New York, Louisiana and the Bahamas.
Frequent Lee collaborator Terence Blanchard composed the score, and the
visual effects were created by Industrial Light & Magic.
Miracle at St.
Anna premiered at the 2008 Toronto International Film Festival
before it was released on September 26, 2008.
It was met with mostly negative reviews from critics and drew
controversy in Italy over historical inaccuracies.
During its theatrical run, Miracle at St.
Anna was a box-office bomb, grossing only $9.3 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of village, world war ii,
soldier, partisan, tuscany, italy.
The tone is emotional.